Can you help me pick an engagement ring?
菲比，帮我挑订婚戒指好吗？
I can't figure this out. Should I get her a Tiffany cut or a princess cut or a..?
我觉得好难挑喔 我要选第凡内切割法还是… 公主方切割法还是…
Paper cut!
纸张切割法
-Have you told anyone else? -No,I don't want Monica to find out.
你有告诉其他人吗？ 没有，我不想让摩妮卡发现
You told me.
可是你告诉我了
Because I trust you and we're friends...
因为我信任你 你是我的死党之一
and you saw me looking at ring brochures.
而且你在我看型录时闯进来
Once again, not knocking pays off.
进房不敲门再次大有斩获
-I wish you hadn't been on the toilet. -Me too.
如果你不是在蹲马桶就好了 我有同感
Let me see. Is there such a thing as a Monica cut?
我看看，有摩妮卡切割法吗？
Because that would be you best bet.
有的话就是它了
-Want to go to the coffeehouse? -Oh,all right.
钱德，要不要去喝咖啡？ 好啊 走吧
We were just gonna see if you wanted to go.
太好了，我们正想找你们下去
Well,we don't because we got the other place.
不要，我们要去别家
How rude.
真没礼貌
Sorry. Want a bite?
抱歉，你要吃吗？
The One With The Ring
本集播出：“完美的戒指”
rainystar压制iPod-MP4
So how are things going with Paul?
你和保罗交往得怎样？
Good.
很好
Although,you know, he's a private guy.
只不过他很内敛
I wish I could get him to open up, share some feelings.
真想让他稍微敞开心胸 分享心情
You just have to think of him as a jar of pickles that won't open.
简单 把他想成打不开的罐子就对了
I should run him under hot water and bang his head against a table?
你要我捉他的头冲热水敲桌子
That's what you do when you want to get the truth out of someone.
不是，那是拷问的手法
-Watch this. -Okay.
看我的 好
-Hey,Paul. -Hi,Phoebe.
-保罗  -菲比
How are things going with you?
你最近好吗？
Can't complain.
没得抱怨
Let's go！
走吧
-Great to.. -Ross,good to see you too.
-很高兴...  -我也很高兴见到你
You take care.
保重
What was the deal with you and Chandler blowing us off before?
你们刚才为什么见到我们就跑
That was so weird,huh?
很怪吧？
Why did you do it?
菲比，为什么？
I didn't do it. It was Chandler.
不是我，是钱德
He's mad at you.
他…他在生你们的气
-What? Why? -Oh,please. I think you know why.
-什么？ 为什么？ -拜托，你明知故问
I can't think of anything.
我想不起来
Come on. You're a paleontologist. Dig a little deeper.
罗斯，你是古生物学家 再往下挖
Is it because Joey and I didn't invite him to that Knicks game?
等等，是不是因为两个星期前 乔伊和我没找他去看球？
Is that something he'd be mad at you for?
你觉得他会为这种事生气吗？
-I guess it could. -Well,then I think that's it.
应该会 那就是罗
If he's angry, he shouldn't hide it. I wish he'd just tell me the truth.
他不该隐瞒他的情绪 他应该老实告诉我
You should run him under hot water and bang his head against the table.
那你应该捉他的头 去冲热水敲桌子
Honey,I made a reservation at China Garden. Is that okay?
我在“中国花园”订了位 可以吗？
Yeah,that's great.
可以啊，很棒
But first,talk to me. Talk to me. Tell me about your day.
但你先跟我说说话 说说你今天好不好
It was fine.
蛮好的
Okay.
好吧
What are you thinking right now?
你在想什么？你现在在想什么
That you are looking really fine in that dress.
我在想你穿这件裙子很好看
Yeah, that's great, Paul. But, you know....
太好了，但是…
I want to know what.. Wow, those are really great!
我想知道…哇，好结实
I just want to know...
我想知道...
what is behind this strong, silent exterior?
这坚强沉默的外表下 隐藏着什么
They say that still waters run deep, and I want to swim in yours.
俗语说静水深流 我想在你的心中畅游
Are you talking about having sex?
你在讲做爱的事吗？
No, Paul.
不是
I don't know anything about you. Tell me about your childhood.
我一点也不了解你 例如你的童年，聊聊你的童年
Normal.
很普通
Then how about puberty? Come on! That's always a painful time.
好，那青春期呢？ 青春期总是很讨厌
Your friends have a slumber party and stick your hand in warm water...
朋友找你去过夜聊天 趁你睡着把你的手放进热水里
while you sleep, so you pee in your sleeping bag.
害你在睡袋里撒尿
No,that never happened to me.
我没碰过那种事
You're lucky you never met that bitch, Sharon Majeski.
那是你走运 没碰上那个贱人莎朗麦杰斯基
Anyway...
总之…
The rest of your life. Any regrets?
其他时期有什么悔恨吗？
Nope.
没有
I'm not asking for a lot here.
保罗，我要求得不多
Just give me something. Anything.
你就讲一件事，什么事都好
-Okay. -Okay.
好吧
When I was 6 years old, I wanted a Big Wheel.
6岁那年 我想要一辆大脚踏车
And instead,my parents got me this little...
我父母却送我一个...
plastic chicken that you hop around on.
小鸡造型的跳跳乐
It was embarrassing. Kids made fun of me.
糗死了，小朋友都笑我
That was a tough year.
那一年蛮痛苦的
That's great! See?
太好了，你看吧
I already feel like I know you a little better.
我觉得我比较了解你了，谢谢
Okay,come on. Now we can go eat. Let's go!
好，我们去吃饭吧
It was horrible.
我好惨
They called me "Chicken Boy."
大家都叫我鸡弟弟
In fifth grade,I got in a fight. Well, not really.
五年级我跟别人打架 其实也不算打架
Richard Danville bit me.
理查达伦咬我的鼻子
I still have a little scar right here. You can see it.
我摔倒 这里留了一个小疤
Yeah,yeah. I see the scar.
有，我看见了
I think this is really great that, you know, you've shared your feelings.
保罗，你听我说 你这样分享你的心情真的很棒
It's really... It's beautiful.
真的很..好
But what do you say we go share some food?
那我们现在去吃饭吧
No,I couldn't eat now.
我现在吃不下
What are you talking about? You love their Kung Pao chicken!
你在说什么？ 你最爱吃宫保鸡丁了
Chicken?
鸡？
-Chicken Boy! -I'm sorry. I didn't mean to do that.
鸡弟弟 天哪，对不起，我不是故意的
This is the nine millionth ring store, and I can't find the perfect ring.
一无所获 逛了几百家店 还是找不到完美的戒指
Ugly ring, ugly ring, ugly ring...
丑，丑，丑
It's a beautiful selection.
这些戒指真美
So maybe you don't get her a ring. Maybe you do something different.
不然你不要送戒指 送点不一样的
An engagement bracelet or an engagement tiara!
例如订婚手镯，或是订婚头饰
An engagement Revolutionary War musket!
订婚独立战争毛瑟枪
I'm so glad I picked you to help me with this.
真高兴我是选你来帮忙
Imagine getting down on one knee...
你能不能想像你单膝跪下
and handing her this gorgeous piece of weaponry?
把这件漂亮的火器交给她？
I'll stick with the ring.
我还是送戒指好了
This one's nice. I like it. Sir?
这只好漂亮，我喜欢这只
Kind sir, can I see this one?
先生？大哥？我想看这枚戒指
This is why you brought me. I know how to haggle.
你找我来就是因为我会讲价
-Let me handle this from here. -Can I help you?
所以接下来交给我处理  有什么需要吗？
-I would like to see that ring. -Or not. Whatever.
有，我想看那枚戒指 或是不看，随便
This ring is from the 1920s.
这是一只20年代的戒指
It's a one and a half carat diamond with sapphires.
1.5克拉，两侧镶有蓝宝石
Sir, could I ask you...?
先生，你能不能…
Could you hold out that ring and ask me to marry you?
拿着戒指向我求婚？
-Okay. -Okay.
好
Will you marry me?
你愿意嫁给我吗？
Oh, my God, that's it! That's the ring!
天哪，就是它了
-How much is it? -I will handle this.
-多少钱？ -钱德，让我来
How much is it?
多少钱？
$8600.
8千6
We will give you $10.
我们出10块钱
-Are you interested in this ring? -Yes.
-你到底想不想买？ -想，想
But I can only pay $8000.
但我只能出8千
-Okay. I can let it go for 8. -We stand firm at $10.
-好，8千可以 -我们坚持10块钱
-How would you like to pay? -Credit card.
您要怎么付帐？ --刷卡
Oh,no! I lent my credit card to Joey.
不对，我的卡在乔伊那边
I'll go get it. You guard the ring.
我回去拿，你守住戒指
-Why did you give your credit card to Joey? -To buy some Knicks tickets.
-你为什么把你的卡给乔伊？ -他要买尼克队的球票
Then the jerk didn't even invite me to the game. But I'm over it. Whatever!
结果他居然没有找我一起去  不过我已经不在意了
Listen, I'm sorry about before.
刚才很抱歉
Do you have anything here for $10?
你们有10块钱的东西吗？
Yes. I have these two rather beautiful...
有，我有两张崭新的...
five-dollar bills.
5元钞票
I'll give you $1 for them.
我出1块钱跟你买
Remember how Chandler and Phoebe blew us off yesterday?
昨天钱德和菲比 不是看到我们就跑？
No.
有吗？
-Remember,you were eating pizza? -Yeah.
你当时在吃披萨 喔对
Chandler's angry at us for not getting him a ticket to that Knicks game.
钱德显然是在气我们2星期前 没帮他买球票
We were supposed to just get him one? That guy's always mooching off of us.
我们为什么要帮他买票？ 那砘锢鲜强我们的油 就是啊
Anyway,I still think we should try to patch things up.
但我还是觉得应该设法和解
We could get tickets to another game and invite him.
我们可以找他去看另一场球赛
That's a great idea. And I still have his credit card.
好主意 而且他的卡还在我这里
Here you go.
帐单
Hey,hey. I got this one. Here you go.
我有卡，拿去吧
Sometimes I just don't get Chandler.
有时候我真搞不懂钱德
We do stuff all the time without you, and you don't get all upset.
我和他做很多事都没找你 你也不会生气
-All the time? -All the time.
很多事？ 可多了
I'm sorry,it was rejected.
抱歉，这张卡不能刷
That's impossible. Let me see that.
不可能，我看看
This one's mine. Here you go.
这张是我的，拿去吧
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
我的天哪  我的天哪
-Still crying? -Like a little girl.
还在哭？ 跟小女生一样
I know,I know. This is all my fault.
我知道…都是我不好
I wanted him to open up.
是我要他敞开心胸的
I didn't know that I was gonna unleash...
但是我不知道我会放出一头...
this weepy,clingy, moist monster!
哭哭啼啼又黏人的怪物
I only know of two ways to shut a man up. One of them is sex.
有两个办法能让一个男人闭嘴 其中一个是性爱
-What's the other? -Don't know. Never had to use it.
-另一个是什么？ -不知道，我只用过第一个
I'm just saying, if we're having sex, he's not talking.
我只是说做爱的时候 他就不能讲话
That's right. You're the talker.
没错，话多的是你
Anyway, great idea.
总之这个主意很棒
I gotta buy him some more tissues.
我要去商店 我答应去帮他买面纸
-We have some here. -No,you don't!
-我们这里有… -你们没有
Okay. I'd also like to try on the tiara.
好，我还想试戴头饰
Oh,yeah. Okay.
太好了
What do you think? Too much?
怎么样？太花了？
A tad.
有一点
Take the tiara back...
把头饰放回去
and let me hold the musket again.
毛瑟枪再给我一次
Something's missing.
少了点什么…
Let me see the ring that my friend picked out.
把我朋友挑的戒指拿给我
-Where's the 1920s princess-cut ring? -I just sold it to that gentleman.
-那枚20年代的钻戒呢？ -刚刚卖给那位先生
Oh,my God!
完蛋了
Wait,no!
等等，别走
Let me out! Now!
放我出去，快点
Rachel?
瑞秋…
No.
不是
-How are you, Paul? -Okay.
保罗，你好吗？ 还好
Chandler...
钱德…
-did your dad ever hug you? -No. Did he hug you?
-你爸抱过你吗？  -没有，他抱过你吗？
No! No.
不是
It's just that my dad never did.
只不过我爸都没抱过我
I miss my dad.
我好想念我爸
You can see my dad in Vegas kissing other dads.
你可以去赌城 看我爸亲别人的爸爸
-Hey,Chandler? -Yeah?
钱德？ 怎样？
Would you...?
你能不能…
Would you hug me?
你能不能抱我？
-I'm a little busy here, Paul. -That's what my dad used to say.
-我有点忙  -我爸也都这么说
Okay. A quick one. Come on, hug it out.
好啦，一下下，快点
There you go.
行了吧
Okay.
好了
-Five more seconds.. -Okay!
-再5秒钟 -够了
-Joey! -What? Hey, what..?
-乔伊  -什么？
Hi. Paul,is it?
保罗是吧？
-Do you have my credit card? -Yeah. It's in my...
我的信用卡在吗？ 在，在我的…
In my pocket.
我的口袋里
-My back pocket! -Thank God.
-后面的口袋 -幸好
-I got tickets to the Knicks tonight. -I can't go.
-我买了今天晚上尼克队的票 -我不能去
It'll be fun.
去啦，多好玩啊
Me, you, Ross and Paul, probably.
我，你，罗斯和… 保罗吗？
Look, I don't have time for this, okay? I gotta go.
我没空好吗，我得走了
That was mean.
好恶劣喔
Yeah,I know.
就是啊
-Get in here. -Yeah.
过来吧 好
Chandler, I found the perfect ring.
钱德，我找到最完美的戒指了
I'm gonna go with the one I picked first.
真不错 但我还是买之前那款好了
Oh, wake up. The one you picked is gone. It's over!
天哪，钱德，那枚戒指不在了
What?
什么？
Some guy bought it. I tried to stop him, but they put me in jail!
被一个人买走了，对不起 我想拦住他，却被关进监狱里
-They put you in jail? -The little jail between the doors!
-被关进监狱里？ -门和门中间的小监狱
-I asked you to guard the ring! -I know. I'm sorry.
-菲比，我要你守着那枚戒指 -我知道，对不起
But this ring is better. And Monica never saw the other ring.
但是这枚比较好 摩妮卡根本没看过另一枚
Yeah,but when he proposed to me with the ring, I got goosebumps.
但是他用那枚戒指向我求婚时 我起了鸡皮疙瘩
-Maybe it was the guy. -It was the ring!
-也许是因为那个人 -是因为那枚戒指
-Was he excited about the tickets? -No! He blew us off!
-他兴奋吗？ -不，他回绝了
-What? -I know.
什么？ 就是啊
I can't believe it.
真是太扯了
Can I tell you something?
告诉你
I'm a little mad at him now!
我现在有点气他
Can I tell you something?
告诉你
Me too!
我也是
He didn't want to talk to us about being angry.
他生气不告诉我们
Maybe we don't talk to him at all!
那我们也不要告诉他
-Freeze him out. -Right!
-把他打入冷宫  -没错
-I like it. -We'll show him.
-我喜欢 -给他好看
From now on,it's gonna be Joey and Ross, best friends.
以后就是乔伊与罗斯 最佳拍档
We'll be the new Joey and Chandler.
我们将是新的乔伊与钱德
What?
什么？
You think you and Chandler were closer than me and Chandler?
你觉得你和钱德比我和钱德更好？
Hey, don't get angry.
别生气
We turn on each other, he wins.
我们一反目，他就赢了
Hi,I'm back.
我回来了
I've written down more to tell you!
我把我想说的话都写下来了
Oh,that's great.
真好
No,actually,that's...
真是太好了
That's great. That's really great.
真的好棒
You know,I gotta tell you, writing, all that writing, it gets me...
说真的，写东西会燃起…
It gets me kind of hot.
我的欲火
Wait, wait. Listen to this:
等等，你听喔
Know what I wanted to be at that age?
你知道我小时候想当什么？
A lover?
情圣？
-A surfer. -A surfer?
-冲浪者 -是吗？
-I wanted to be one with the waves.. -Hold on.
-我想与海浪为伍  -等等，等一下
Let me just get a little more comfortable here.
让我把自己弄得舒服一点
Wait a second.
等一下
-This isn't too revealing,is it? -No.
-这样会不会太露了？  -不会
Whatever happened to that little dude?
当年那个小砘锬兀
So full of dreams.
充满梦想…
I don't care about the little dude!
我不在乎那个小砘
I can't! I cannot listen to any more of this!
我听不下去了
The only one who'd listen is a mental health professional!
只有心理医师会想听这些话
That's only because they get $100 an hour!
那还是因为他们1小时赚1百
Do you know how much money I could have made listening to you? $2000!
你知道我听到现在可以赚多少  2千块！
Know when I figured that out? While you were talking!
你知道我什么时候算出来的？ 在你碎碎念的时候
I can't believe you're trying to stifle me when 14 hours ago...
你居然想扼杀我的情绪 14个小时前...
we figured out that's what my mother was trying to do!
我们才发现那就是我妈的目的
I'm sorry.
对不起
I don't mean... I didn't mean to stifle you.
我不是想扼杀你的情绪
This is all just a little overwhelming.
我只是有点受不了
I'm so sorry.
瑞秋，对不起
I didn't mean to overwhelm you.
我不是故意的
It's just that when those gates open...
只不过情绪一发泄
it's hard to close them.
就会…不可收拾
But they are closed now. Believe me.
不过现在没事了，真的
I'm so glad. I'm so glad you shared.
我很高兴你跟我分享你的心情
And I'm glad that you're done.
也很高兴你分享完了
So what do you say we....
那我们要不要…
I'd like that.
我求之不得
That was so good!
真是…太棒了
Oh,oh.
I can't believe you talked me into this gumball-machine-looking ring.
我居然听你的话 买下这枚造型廉价的戒指
It's not a gumball-machine-looking ring. It's a beautiful ring!
它才没有造型廉价，它很漂亮
No, it's not.
它才不漂亮
When I looked at the other ring, I could see Monica's face...
另一枚戒指 会让我看到摩妮卡的表情
and I could see her saying yes. Looking at this,I only see a ring.
我会看到她点头答应 这枚戒指只让我看到一枚戒指
Unless I look at it really closely, and then I can see my own eye.
只有近看才会看到我自己的眼睛
This is the most important thing I'll ever do. I want to make it perfect.
这是我这辈子最重要的一件事 我想做到最完美
Maybe we could get the other ring back.
我们或许能把那枚戒指要回来
I heard where the guy was gonna propose.
我偷听到那个人准备求婚的地方
-Maybe we could get him to trade rings. -I can't do that.
-或许我们可以说服他交换  -我不能这么做
You certainly can't give her that stupid gumball ring.
你总不能给她那枚廉价的戒指
-All right. Where was he going? -Yeah,it's a restaurant...
-好吧，他要去哪里？ -一家餐厅…
-The Rainbow something. -Rainbow Room? -No.
-彩虹什么的  -彩虹餐厅？ -不是
-Rainbow Grill? -No.
-彩虹烧烤？ -不是
Somewhere Over the...?
彩虹的彼端？（电影“绿野仙踪”主题曲）
-L'Espace. -Rainbow L'Espace!
-空间  -彩虹空间？
No,just L'Espace.
不是，只有空间
I'd love to know how you got from rainbow to L'Espace.
你是怎么从彩虹跳到空间的
No, you wouldn't.
你不会想知道的
You don't wanna get in here.
我的思路很复杂
There he is.
就是他
He hasn't proposed yet. She has no ring on.
好，他还没求婚 因为她没有戴戒指
Wow, you're good! After this, we should solve crimes.
你真行，我们应该去当侦探
Okay. Go get him.
没错 去请他过来
Oh,okay.
好
Excuse me. Could you come with me? You have a phone call.
抱歉，请您来一下 有您的电话
-Who is it? -It's your office.
是谁？ 是你的公司打来的
-Do you know who at my office? -John.
-你知道是谁吗？ -约翰？
Oh,John! Great!
约翰啊，太好了
-There he is. -Hi. Okay.
-他来了 -你好
There was a mix-up at the store.
珠宝店搞错了
The ring you have was supposed to be held for me.
他们把为我保留的戒指卖给你
I'm gonna need to have that back.
所以我得跟你要回来
In exchange, I'm willing to trade you this beautiful, more expensive ring.
不过我愿意拿这枚美丽的 更昂贵的戒指和你交换
Wow, I would trade.
要是我就换
It is beautiful, but I'm gonna use this one. Excuse me.
的确很美，但是我要用这一枚 失陪了
This is my fiancee, and her heart was set on that ring.
不，这位是我的未婚妻 她就是要这枚戒指
Do you want to break her heart?
你不会想伤她的心吧？
Yeah. Do you want to break a dying woman's heart?
对啊 你想伤一位垂死女人的心吗？
You're dying?
你要死了？
Yeah,she's dying...
她快死于…
of a cough,apparently.
咳嗽了
It's my dying wish to have that ring. If I'm not buried with it...
对，我临死前想拥有那枚戒指 要是不能戴着它入土
my spirit will wander the netherworld..
我会变成孤魂野鬼在阴间…
That's enough!
够了，亲爱的
Oh,I don't know.
我不晓得
-Let me see it. -Great. Okay, here.
-再让我看一次  -当然，请看
-All right,I'll do it. -Thank you.
-好吧  -谢谢，谢谢，谢谢
And you are about to marry a wonderful man.
你即将嫁给一个大好人
Hey, I'm marrying a dead woman!
我要娶一个死人
Guys?
兄弟们？
I've got something important to tell you.
我有大事要宣布
Guys?
兄弟们？
I'm gonna ask Monica to marry me.
我要跟摩妮卡求婚了
I think we gotta end the freeze-out.
我们应该让他从冷宫出来
Wait. Is this for real?
等等，你是来真的？
Yeah. Check out the ring.
对，戒指在这里
Oh,my God!
天哪
So you two are really serious?
你们真的是认真的？
Yeah, pretty much.
差不多
You're gonna get married?
你们要结婚了？
We're gonna be brothers-in-law! Come here!
我们要成为连襟了，过来
And we're gonna be friends again.
我们又可以当朋友了
What?
什么？
-Water under the bridge! Forget it! -Okay.
-过去的事就别提了 -好吧
I was gonna wait till it was official, but I had to tell you guys.
我本来想等搞定再说 但我还是忍不住要告诉你们
You're my best friends.
因为你们是我的死党
-I can't believe this. -Me too.
-我真不敢相信  -我也是
I was planning on having a conversation with you about your intentions.
我本来还想问你有什么打算
I think I'm gonna cry.
我要哭了
Oh! No more crying!
别再哭了，拜托
I just dumped one crybaby. I'll dump you too.
我刚甩掉一个爱哭宝宝 小心我也甩了你
I'm gonna ask Monica to marry me.
我要跟摩妮卡求婚
Oh,my God!
我的天哪
Oh,Chandler! You guys are gonna be so happy!
钱德，你们会好幸福
-I know. -Where's all the tissues?!
-我知道  -面纸都死哪去了？
-Check out the ring. -Oh, nice. One and a half carat, easy.
-这是戒指  -真好，至少有1.5克拉
-Hey. -Hey,Phoebe.
菲比
-He's gonna ask Monica to marry him. -Oh, I know. I helped pick out the ring.
-钱德要跟摩妮卡求婚了 -我知道，是我陪他去挑戒指的
You told her before you told us?
你先告诉她？
She walked in while I was looking at brochures. You can understand that.
我在看戒指型录时被她撞见 你们能谅解吧？
Guys?
兄弟们？
God, that ring Chandler picked out was so beautiful.
天哪，钱德选的戒指好美
You should know. You've bought like a billion of them.
你当然识货，你买过一大堆
Humor based on my pain.
拿我的痛处开玩笑
You know what's funny?
有趣的是
Of all of your wives, I'm the only one who never got a ring.
你的老婆里只有我没拿到戒指
This a big issue for you?
你很在意吗？
No, but it would have been nice to have a little memento...
不是，只不过如果能有纪念品
of our married time together.
总是蛮好的
Something other than the divorce papers and the hangover.
而不要只有离婚证书和宿醉
Ross is obviously not gonna get you a ring.
罗斯显然不会送你戒指
But ask for a musket. Ask for a musket!
不过跟他要毛瑟枪
When we were married, do you know what I never got?
你知道我们结婚时 少做了什么事？
Sex.
上床
Well,yeah. No ring,no sex. Big surprise.
没戒指当然没得做，你还敢提
Get me a musket and we'll talk.
送我毛瑟枪，一切好谈